[music]
[Instructor] All right
so our Particles are
getting pretty good right now.
When we run into one of these Obstacles
we get that big puff of smoke.
So we're going to add a little
bit more to our character.
So we have this cool
"FX_DirtSplatter" Effect.
So we're actually just going
to drag this onto our Player.
And now we have that dirt
Particle Effect.
Now it does look a little weird.
You can see it's like spitting
out in front,
and in this case to the side.
That's not really how running works,
so we're going to make it so
that we can face this dirtParticle
to the back. So what we'll actually do,
we're just going to use our
"Rotate Tool" in the top-left,
and we're just going to Rotate
this I think on our Z-Axis.
There you go.
Looks pretty good now.
Probably like directly to the back.
Cool, looks good. If you want to,
I'm just going to clean
up this value in our Rotation,
so I'll set it to -90
that way it's definitely facing
backwards.
Then if you want you can even mess
with the Y-Rotation
and make it face a bit more upwards
or downwards if you want to.
Up to you.
Really whatever you want to do.
I think that angle
is pretty fine for me.
And then we're going to go
into our PlayerController
Script, once again.
And then,
in our PlayerController Script
just like we did
with our explosionParticle,
we're going to make
a public ParticleSystem,
so that way we can attach it.
And then this will just be we'll call
it "dirtParticle," very simple.
And then what we actually
want to happen is
when we're jumping,
we actually don't want
to Play our dirtParticle anymore,
so it's always Playing already.
So we'll actually set our dirtParticle.
See dirtParticle,
so we can Play,
so I wonder if we go
to the options is there,
so we can "Stop()"
so that seems pretty helpful.
So let's Stop()
our Particle from Playing,
and then when the Player
lands back on the Ground
that's when we want
it to start again.
So we'll "Play()"
when we touch the Ground.
And then it would look pretty weird
if dirt was still coming
out from behind the Player
if the game was over,
and they died,
so we're just going to
Stop() that Particle
from Playing when they
run into an Obstacle.
Now when we save, so you can see
when we go back into Unity, in fact,
the Play on Awake* is
actually set to on
for our DirtSplatter which is fine,
so that you can see it when
the game actually starts,
and then when we press Play,
you can see we're running,
we're running, we're making dirt,
and then we jump, and we're
still making dirt somehow.
Maybe it's stuck to
the Player's shoes.
That probably doesn't
make any sense.
Well, the explosion still
works so that's cool.
Now you can see that there's just
magical dirt
being thrown out into the sky.
Maybe there's like an
animal underneath the Player that's
actually creating the dirt, who knows?
I think we actually, we might
of skipped a step as you can see.
Oh so,
in the bottom we have an error,
so dirtParticle
has not been assigned.
So I believe, in Player, ah see,
so under our
PlayerController Script
we didn't actually give
it a Dirt Particle,
so we'll just take the
DirtSplatter, drag it, drop it.
Now, when we press Play.
The dirt starts which is great
and then we jump, and no dirt
and then there's dirt, and
then no dirt, no dirt.
There's dirt, and then
we run in and explosion.
And no dirt, perfect.
Cool, so we're really running now.
So what you're going to do
is you're going to take
one of the DirtSplatter Particles,
drag and drop it onto the Player.
And then you can just set
it's "Position" and Rotation
to make sure that it looks like
it's actually coming out from behind
the Player.
So in our PlayerController class,
we're going to make sure
that we create
another ParticleSystem
variable for our dirtParticle.
In our Update() method,
whenever we're jumping
we want to make sure we Stop()
Playing that dirtParticle;
otherwise, it would look very strange
that there's just magical dirt
flying in the sky.
When we hit the Ground,
we're going to Play()
that dirtParticle again.
And then when we hit an Obstacle,
since we're no longer running
we Stop() Playing it once again.
And then in Unity,
just make sure
that on your Player Object
you drag and drop the DirtSplatter,
and add it to the Dirt Particle
in our PlayerController Script.
Now it's your turn
[music]